Frédéric Louis Ritter Item Scans and Papers MS096
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Frédéric Louis Ritter Item Scans and Papers
1527 -- 1862
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
MS096
0.25 Linear Feet
34 Volumes
221 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in three series: Scores; Texts; Ritter primary source and collection documents.
Custodial History
Material in series 3 was pulled from the DCA collection documentation file, originally MS014, in June 2011. Please refer to collection documentation file MS096 for material regarding missing Ritter items over the years, preservation concerns, NEH grant material (2003) among others.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains papers of Frédéric Louis Ritter and select scanned images of the musical scores and texts from the Frédéric Louis Ritter collection, Special Collections, Tisch Library, which is not a DCA collection. Items listed in the finding aid reflect only the digitized portions of the collection and supporting papers and collection documentation.
Series 3 contains a few letters, historical catalogs of the Ritter collection circa 1940 (already intermixed with the overall Albert Metcalf collection), and a score fragment (unknown composer and language.)
Biographical / Historical
Frederic Louis Ritter (1834-1891) was a German composer and author. After Ritter's death, Albert Metcalf bought Ritter's music collection, and donated it to Tufts University. Frederic Louis Ritter was born in Strasbourg, France, on June 22, 1834. Growing up, Ritter studied both French and Germanic styles of music. At the age of 18, he was appointed to be a professor of music at the Protestant Seminary of Fénéstrange. Ritter immigrated to the United States in 1856 at the age of 23, following his relatives; at the time, he was noted to possess an extraordinarily large music collection. Initially, Ritter moved to Cincinnati, where he founded the Cecilia and Philharmonic Societies. He moved to New York City in 1862, and had a large influence over the musical scene. There, he directed both the Sacred Harmonic and Arion Choral Societies, and organized "what is considered to be the city's first music festival" at Steinway Hall in 1867. He was made a Professor of Music at Vassar College in the same year, and rose to become Director of the department in 1878. He was awarded an honorary Doctor of Music in 1877 from New York University. Ritter died in Antwerp, Belgium, on July 6, 1891. Soon after Ritter's death, Albert Metcalf purchased Ritter's music collection, containing rare musical scores and texts. Metcalf continued to add to the collection after Ritter's death, and donated the entire collection to Tufts as the Albert Metcalf Musical Library, on November 27, 1901.
Related Materials
For more information on the books of the Ritter collection, the
Tisch Library online catalog
should be consulted.
Ritter, Frédéric Louis; Music
- Scores, 1688 -- 1862; MS096.001; 15 Volumes; 187 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains select scanned images of musical scores from the Frédéric Louis Ritter collection, Special Collections, Tisch Library, which is not a DCA collection. Most scores date from the 18th century and are by composers such as Franz Schubert, Carl Bach, Jean Phillippe Rameau, and Joseph Mehul.
  Items listed in this series reflect only the digitized portions of the scores.
  Arrangement
  This series is not arranged.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  Related Materials
  For more information on the Ritter collection, the
  Tisch Library online catalog
  should be consulted.
  - Die Winterreise, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    This is an image book created from the score of Die Winterreise by Franz Schubert, with the lyrics in both German and French. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Die winterreise, cover, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00001; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
      Page image from Die Winterreise, 1827. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Die winterreise, inside cover, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00002 (Box 1)
      From Die Winterreise, 1827. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Die winterreise, title page, No. 1, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00003 (Box 1)
    - Die winterreise, Gute Nacht, page 3, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00004; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die winterreise, Gute Nacht, page 4, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00005; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die winterreise, Gute Nacht, page 5, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00006; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die winterreise, Gute Nacht, page 6, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00007; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die winterreise, Gute Nacht, page 7, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00008; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die winterreise, title page, No. 2, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00009; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Wetterfahne, page 8, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00010; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Wetterfahne, page 9, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00011; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Wetterfahne, page 10, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00012; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 3, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00013; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Gefrorne Thranen, page 11, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00014; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Gefrorne Thranen, page 12, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00015; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Gefrorne Thranen, page 13, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00016; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 4, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00017; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Erstarrung, page 14, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00018; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Erstarrung, page 15, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00019; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Erstarrung, page 16, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00020; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Erstarrung, page 17, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00021; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Erstarrung, page 18, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00022; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Erstarrung, page 19, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00023; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Erstarrung, page 20, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00024; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 5, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00025; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Lindenbaum, page 21, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00026; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Lindenbaum, page 22, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00027; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Lindenbaum, page 23, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00028; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Lindenbaum, page 24, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00029; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Lindenbaum, page 25, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00030; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 6, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00031; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Wasserfluth, page 26, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00032; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Wasserfluth, page 27, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00033; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Wasserfluth, page 28, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00034; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Wasserfluth, page 29, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00035; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 7, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00036; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Auf dem Flusse, page 30, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00037; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Auf dem Flusse, page 31, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00038; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Auf dem Flusse, page 32, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00039; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Auf dem Flusse, page 33, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00040; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 8, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00041; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Ruckblick, page 34, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00042; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Ruckblick, page 35, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00043; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Ruckblick, page 36, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00044; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Ruckblick, page 37, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00045; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Ruckblick, page 38, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00046; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 9, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00047; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Jrrlicht, page 39, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00048; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Jrrlicht, page 40, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00049; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 10, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00050; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Rast, page 41, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00051; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Rast, page 42, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00052; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Rast, page 43, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00053; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 11, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00054; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Fruhlingstraum, page 44, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00055; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Fruhlingstraum, page 45, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00056; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Fruhlingstraum, page 46, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00057; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Fruhlingstraum, page 47, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00058; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Fruhlingstraum, page 48, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00059; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 12, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00060; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Einsamkeit, page 49, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00061; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Einsamkeit, page 50, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00062; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 13, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00063; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Post, page 51, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00064; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Post, page 52, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00065; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Post, page 53, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00066; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Post, page 54, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00067; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Post, page 55, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00068; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 14, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00069; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der greise Kopf, page 56, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00070; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der greise Kopf, page 57, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00071; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der greise Kopf, page 58, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00072; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 15, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00073; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Krahe, page 59, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00074; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Krahe, page 60, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00075; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Krahe, page 61, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00076; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Krahe, page 62, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00077; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 16, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00078; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Letze Hoffnung, page 63, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00079; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Letze Hoffnung, page 64, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00080; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Letze Hoffnung, page 65, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00081; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Letze Hoffnung, page 66, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00082; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 17, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00083; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Im Dorfe, page 67, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00084; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Im Dorfe, page 68, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00085; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Im Dorfe, page 69, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00086; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Im Dorfe, page 70, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00087; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Im Dorfe, page 71, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00088; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Im Dorfe, page 72, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00089; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 18, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00090; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Stürmische Morgen, page 73, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00091; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Strmische Morgen, page 74, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00092; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Strmische Morgen, page 75, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00093; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 19, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00094; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Tauschung, page 76, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00095; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Tauschung, page 77, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00096; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Tauschung, page 78, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00097; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 20, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00098; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Wegweiser, page 79, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00099; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Wegweiser, page 80, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00100; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Wegweiser, page 81, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00101; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Wegweiser, page 82, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00102; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Wegweiser, page 83, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00103; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 21, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00104; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Das Wirthshaus, page 84, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00105; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Das Wirthshaus, page 85, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00106; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Das Wirthshaus, page 86, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00107; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 22, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00108; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Muth, page 87, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00109; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Muth, page 88, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00110; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Muth, page 89, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00111; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 23, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00112; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Nebensonnen, page 90, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00113; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Die Nebensonnen, page 91, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00114; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, title page, No. 24, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00115; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Leiermann, page 92, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00116; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Leiermann, page 93, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00117; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, Der Leiermann, page 94, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00118; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
    - Die Winterreise, back cover, 1827; MS096.001.001.00001.00119; Schubert, Franz (Box 1)
  - Thesee, Tragedie Mise En Musique, De Lully, 1688 -- 1720; MS096.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
    - Thesee, title page, 1720; MS096.001.002.00001.00001; Lully, Jean-Baptiste (Box 2)
      Page image from Lully's Thesee. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
      Music
    - Thesee, prologue, 1720; MS096.001.002.00001.00002; Lully, Jean-Baptiste (Box 2)
    - Thesee, page 124, 1720; MS096.001.002.00001.00003; Lully, Jean-Baptiste (Box 2)
    - Thesee, page 159, 1720; MS096.001.002.00001.00004; Lully, Jean-Baptiste (Box 2)
    - Thesee, page iv, catalogue, 1720; MS096.001.002.00001.00005; Lully, Jean-Baptiste (Box 2)
    - Thesee, page 1 of Prologue in 1688 edition, MS096.001.002.00001.00006; Lully, Jean-Baptiste (Box 2)
    - Thesee, page ii - Airs jouer, 1720; MS096.001.002.00001.00007; Lully, Jean-Baptiste (Box 2)
    - Thesee, page iii - Airs chanter, 1720; MS096.001.002.00001.00008; Lully, Jean-Baptiste (Box 2)
  - Sechs Sonaten, Versuche uber d. wahre art d. Clavier zu spielen, MS096.001.003.00001; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    Music; Composers; Ritter, Frederick Louis
    - Sechs Sonaten, title page, MS096.001.003.00001.00001; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, TAB I, MS096.001.003.00001.00002; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, TAB II, MS096.001.003.00001.00003; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, TAB III, MS096.001.003.00001.00004; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, TAB IV, MS096.001.003.00001.00005; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, TAB V, MS096.001.003.00001.00006; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, TAB VI, MS096.001.003.00001.00007; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata I, Allegreto, MS096.001.003.00001.00008; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata I, Andante, MS096.001.003.00001.00009; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata I, Tempo di Minuetto, MS096.001.003.00001.00010; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata II, Allegro, MS096.001.003.00001.00011; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata II, Adagio, MS096.001.003.00001.00012; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata II, Presto, MS096.001.003.00001.00013; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata III, Poco Allegro, MS096.001.003.00001.00014; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata III, Andante, MS096.001.003.00001.00015; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata III, Allegro, MS096.001.003.00001.00016; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata IV, Allegretto, MS096.001.003.00001.00017; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata IV, Largo, MS096.001.003.00001.00018; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata IV, Allegro Siciliano, MS096.001.003.00001.00019; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata V, Allegrodi, MS096.001.003.00001.00020; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata V, Allegrodi, MS096.001.003.00001.00021; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata V, Allegretto, MS096.001.003.00001.00022; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata V, Allegretto, cont., MS096.001.003.00001.00023; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata VI, Allegro di molto, MS096.001.003.00001.00024; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata VI, Adagio, MS096.001.003.00001.00025; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata VI, Fantasia, MS096.001.003.00001.00026; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
    - Sechs Sonaten, Sonata VI, Fantasia, cont., MS096.001.003.00001.00027; Bach, Carl Phillip Emanuel (Box 3)
  - Hippolite et Aricie, 1733 -- 1862; MS096.001.004.00001; Rameau, Jean Philippe (Box 4)
    - Inscription, 1862; MS096.001.004.00001.00001 (Box 4)
      Illustration from Rameau's Hippolite et Aricie. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Title page, 1733; MS096.001.004.00001.00002 (Box 4)
      Page from Rameau's Hippolite et Aricie. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Trio des Praques, page 84, 1733; MS096.001.004.00001.00003 (Box 4)
    - Trio des Praques, page 85, 1733; MS096.001.004.00001.00004 (Box 4)
    - Trio des Praques, page pinned over page 83, 1733; MS096.001.004.00001.00005 (Box 4)
  - Iphigenie en Aulis, MS096.001.005.00001; Gluck, Christoph Willibald (Box data_value_missing_d8e260fe8b7fd99197f04c4dec6d5df9)
    - Business card, front, MS096.001.005.00001.00001 (Box data_value_missing_d8e260fe8b7fd99197f04c4dec6d5df9)
      Illustration from Gluck's Iphigenie en Aulis. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
      Advertisements
    - Business card, back, MS096.001.005.00001.00002 (Box data_value_missing_d8e260fe8b7fd99197f04c4dec6d5df9)
  - Pygmalion, 1748; MS096.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
    Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Page 13, 1748; MS096.001.006.00001.00001 (Box 6)
      Page from Rameau's Pygmalion. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Page 23, 1748; MS096.001.006.00001.00002 (Box 6)
    - Page 24, 1748; MS096.001.006.00001.00003 (Box 6)
    - Overture, 1748; MS096.001.006.00001.00004 (Box 6)
  - Le Roi et let fermier, 1762; MS096.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
    - Title page, 1762; MS096.001.007.00001.00001 (Box 7)
      Page from Le Roi et le fermier. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Page 49, 1762; MS096.001.007.00001.00002 (Box 7)
    - Act 1, page 10, 1762; MS096.001.007.00001.00003 (Box 7)
    - Page 27, 1762; MS096.001.007.00001.00004 (Box 7)
  - Stratonice, 1792; MS096.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
    - Back of the title page, 1792; MS096.001.008.00001.00001 (Box 8)
      Page from Stratonice. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Title page, 1792; MS096.001.008.00001.00002 (Box 8)
  - Julie, 1772; MS096.001.009.00001 (Box 9)
    - Advertisements page 1, 1772; MS096.001.009.00001.00001; Monvel (Box 9)
      A page from Julie. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Advertisements page 2, 1772; MS096.001.009.00001.00002; Monvel (Box 9)
    - Titlepage, 1772; MS096.001.009.00001.00003; Monvel (Box 9)
  - Le Deserteur, MS096.001.010.00001 (Box 10)
    - Page 86, Act II scene 5, MS096.001.010.00001.00001; Monvel (Box 10)
      A page from Le Deserteur. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
  - Zemire et Azor, MS096.001.011.00001; Gretry, Andre (Box 11)
    - Titlepage, MS096.001.011.00001.00001 (Box 11)
      Page from Zemire et Azor. No Date Available. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Illustration of tableau magique, MS096.001.011.00001.00002 (Box 11)
      Page from Zemire et Azor. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
  - Iphigénie en Aulide, MS096.001.012.00001; Gluck (Box data_value_missing_d8e260fe8b7fd99197f04c4dec6d5df9)
    - Title page, MS096.001.012.00001.00001 (Box data_value_missing_d8e260fe8b7fd99197f04c4dec6d5df9)
      Page from Gluck Iphigénie en Aulide. No Date Available. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Dedication, MS096.001.012.00001.00002 (Box data_value_missing_d8e260fe8b7fd99197f04c4dec6d5df9)
      Page from Gluck Iphigénie en Aulide. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
  - Roland, 1778; MS096.001.013.00001; Piccinni (Box 13)
    - Title page, 1778; MS096.001.013.00001.00001; Piccinni (Box 13)
      Page from Piccinni Roland. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Dedication, 1778; MS096.001.013.00001.00002; Piccinni (Box 13)
    - Page 291, 1778; MS096.001.013.00001.00003; Piccinni (Box 13)
      Music; score
    - Page 292, 1778; MS096.001.013.00001.00004; Piccinni (Box 13)